Raymond Spilman Papers
Raymond Spilman Papers
1933-1976
Spilman, Raymond, 1911-
96.0 linear ft., 146.0 cubic ft.
Papers of the American industrial designer. Business records and financial and legal materials relating to Spilman's company, Raymond Spilman Industrial Design; and personal papers.
148682
Biographical History
Raymond Spilman (1911-2000) was an American industrial designer.
Born in Wichita, Kansas, Spilman attended Kansas State University from 1933-1934. He worked for General Motors as a stylist from 1935 to 1939, joined Walter Dorwin Teague Associates in 1940 as a staff designer, and worked for Henry Dreyfuss Associates in New York. In 1942 he joined Johnson/Cushing/Nevell as director of product design before opening his own office in 1946.
Spilman was a Fellow and President (1960-1962) of the American Society of Industrial Designers (ASID), and became a Fellow of the Industrial Design Society of America (IDSA) when the two organizations merged in 1965. He also served as educational advisor and lecturer in the field of design and design curriculum.
[Portions of this biographical sketch adapted from Spilman's bio on the IDSA website.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Raymond Spilman Papers consists of several parts which have not been integrated.
Part I
The bulk of the material in Part I is concerned with industrial design for various companies during the 1960's. It comprises three series: business files, financial files, and personal files. Business files includes correspondence, sketches, and models and is arranged alphabetically, apart from material in Boxes 42 and 90 which is in no particular order (it is listed alphabetically in the inventory below, however, to facilitate location). The subseries Artwork and charts, Product models and samples, and Rolled charts and drawings (Boxes 43-89 and 91, and Oversize packages 1-56) are listed at the end of the inventory. They are arranged in no particular order in the packages, but are listed alphabetically in the inventory below to facilitate locating a particular project.
Financial files includes all types of financial and legal material pertaining to his company, Raymond Spilman Industrial Design, and is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically.
Personal files contains material which does not pertain to Mr. Spilman's business matters and deals mainly with his interests and hobbies outside of industrial design.
Part II
Part II comprises five series: correspondence, subject files, manuscripts, printed matter, and Spilman Designs drawings. Correspondence contains both incoming and outgoing correspondence as well as resumes of designers. Subject files contain correspondence, plans, photographs, printed material, and items related to design jobs. Manuscripts consists of addresses, notes and sketches. Printed material includes advertisements, articles, studies, reference catalogs, and other published items. Spilman Designs drawings contains oversize drawings, designs, and renderings for various projects.
Note that in Part II, box numbers restart with "Box 1" in each series. Please specify the series and box number when requesting an item.
Books and Tapes
The collection also contains ten boxes of Books comprising Spilman's personal library, and approximately 135 Tapes. The tapes contain reminiscences, reflections, interviews, and discussions; besides Spilman, the tapes include other designers such as Arthur J. Pulos and John Vassos. Researcher access to the tapes requires advance notice in order to produce a working copy.
Arrangement of the Collection
See Scope and contents, above.
Related Material
has the papers of numerous individuals and organizations significant in the field of industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Industrial Design; Bach, Alfons, 1904-1999.; BecVar, Arthur.; Diffrient, Niels.; Dreyfuss, Henry, 1904-1972.; Kibble, Edward.; Lamb, Thomas B.; Pulos, Arthur J.; Renwick, William Crosby.; Sinel, Joseph.; Spilman, Raymond, 1911-; Vassos, John, 1898-1985.; Viemeister, Read.; Wright, Russel, 1904-1976.; Raymond Spilman Industrial Design.; Industrial design -- United States.; Industrial designers -- United States.; Audiocassettes.; Bank statements.; Bills of sale.; Correspondence.; Oral histories (literary works); Photographs.; Sketches.; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings.; Time sheets.; Industrial designers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Researcher access to the tapes requires advance notice in order to produce a working copy.
Inventory
- Business files (Part I)
  - Acceptance of Employment Conditions (Box 1)
  - Addresses (Box 1)
  - Advancement of Food Service Research Conference Transcript, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Advertising (Box 1)
  - Air-Shields, Inc., 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Albee-Campbell, Inc., 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - Albright Art Gallery Speech, 1959-1963 (Box 1)
  - Alcoa, 1964-1971 (Box 1)
  - All-Steel Furniture, Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Almar Industries, Inc.
    - 1963, 1965-1969, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Sketches (Box 1)
  - AMA Seminar, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - AMA Talk, 1967 (Box 1)
  - AM, 1958-1959
    - Billing (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Personal (Box 1)
    - Progress Report (Box 1)
    - 200, Sheerline Desks (Box 1)
    - 201 (Box 1)
    - 300, Sheerline Chairs (Box 1)
    - 401, Trademark (Box 1)
  - AM-C Consultation, 1958 (Box 1)
  - American Craftsman Council, 1966 (Box 1)
  - American Management Association, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - American Oil Company, 1962 (Box 1)
  - American Sterilizer Co.
    - AMS-10, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Billing Folder, 1963-1966 (Box 1)
    - Brochures (Box 1)
    - Competitive Ads, 1964-1967 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964-1967 (Box 1)
    - Proposals, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Stock, 1964 (Box 1)
  - AMS-1
    - Pages to be Completed (Box 1)
    - Photographed Charts (Box 1)
    - Project Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - Typography (Box 1)
  - AMS-1, AMS-2, design prints (Box 1)
  - AMS-2, 1963 (Box 2)
  - AMS-3, 1962-1964
    - Baarinc Development (Box 2)
    - Color Swatches (Box 2)
    - Completed Art (Box 2)
    - Control Components (Box 2)
    - Control Locations (Box 2)
    - Dials (Box 2)
    - Door Hinging (Box 2)
    - Existing Control Panels (Box 2)
    - Finishes, Color (Box 2)
    - Hi-Lo Valve Handle (Box 2)
    - Industrial Lens (Box 2)
    - Loading Car (Box 2)
    - Manual Control Indicator Disk (Box 2)
    - Panel Legends (Box 2)
    - Photo Marking Trial Sample (Box 2)
    - Push Buttons (Box 2)
    - Spare Pressure Gauge (Box 2)
    - Spare Prints (Box 2)
    - Spare Project Color Swatches (Box 2)
    - Sterilizer Indicator Lights and Push Buttons (Box 2)
    - Symbols (Box 2)
    - Typography (Box 2)
    - C. Project Data (Box 2)
    - D. Project Status (Box 2)
    - E. Project Correspondence (Box 2)
    - E. 1, September 30, 1963 (Box 2)
    - E. 2, October 1-December 31, 1963 (Box 2)
    - E. 3, January 1-February 29, 1964 (Box 2)
    - F. Rough Notes (Box 2)
    - G. Project Specification (Box 2)
    - H. Photographs (Box 2)
    - I. Photographs (Box 2)
    - J. Client Catalogues (Box 2)
    - M. Roughing In, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - N. Drawings List (Box 2)
    - N. Design Prints (Box 2)
    - O. Rough Sketches (Box 2)
    - Q. Components (Box 2)
    - S. Finishes (Box 2)
    - T. Client Graphics (Box 3)
    - V. Intermediate Prints (Box 3)
    - W. Originals and Masters (Box 3)
    - X. Graphics (Box 3)
  - AMS-3, AMS-6, nameplate art work (Box 3)
  - AMS-6
    - Nameplates (Box 3)
    - Preliminary Studies (Box 3)
    - Preliminary Typesetting (Box 3)
  - AMS-7, 1964; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - AMS-8, 1964 (Box 3)
  - AMS-9, 1964 (Box 3)
  - AMS-10, 1964
    - Baarinc (Box 3)
    - Current Work (Box 3)
    - Graphics, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - AMS-11, 1964 (Box 3)
  - AMS-11 and -12, 1964 (Box 3)
  - AMS-12, 1964; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - AMSCO
    - Annual Report, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Art and Design Supplies, 1963 (Box 3)
    - Art Work, 1963 (Box 3)
    - Broken Analysis (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - Drawings and Photos (Box 3)
    - Drawings Format (Box 3)
    - Drawing and Job Numbers (Box 3)
    - Employment Application Form, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Engineering Pictures (Box 3)
    - Equipment Needed (Box 3)
    - General, 1963 (Box 3)
    - General Reference, 1963-1964
      - B. Client Data (Box 3)
      - C. Project Data (Box 3)
      - E. Project Correspondence (Box 3)
      - F. Rough Notes (Box 3)
      - G. Project Specification (Box 3)
      - J. Client Catalogues (Box 3)
      - K. Printed Bulletins (Box 3)
      - M. Client Prints (Box 3)
      - P. Competition (Box 3)
      - Q. Components (Box 3)
      - S. Finishes (Box 3)
      - T. Client Graphics (Box 3)
    - Human Factors Article, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Logo, 1963-1965; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Maintenance Manual, 1963 (Box 3)
    - Meeting, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Meeting, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963-1968 (Box 4)
    - Office Decoration, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Periodical Filing, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Presidential Meeting Graphics, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
    - President's Letterhead (Box 4)
    - Production Finishes Colors, 1963 (Box 4)
    - Project Information File Chart (Box 4)
    - Projects File General Reference, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Talk, 1963 (Box 4)
    - Trademark, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Trademark Paste-Ups (Box 4)
    - Trademark Prior Double Bar (Box 4)
  - AMS-200 Security Steel Chairs, 1958 (Box 4)
  - AND-1, Gourmet, 1969 (Box 4)
  - AND-2, Grater (Phase III), 1969 (Box 4)
  - AND-3, Surveys, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Androck
    - Baseball Bike Carrier Patent Application, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Bicycle Baskets, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Bike Basket Survey, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Catalogues, 1959-1970; 3 folders, 1 issue (Box 4)
    - Contract, 1966-1969 (Box 4)
    - Directory of Personnel, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
    - Egg Basket, 1969 (Box 4)
    - General Correspondence, 1965-1969; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Meeting Report, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1970; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Sales Bulletins, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Washburn Patents, 1965 (Box 5)
    - Washburn Company Typography (Box 5)
  - Androck Limited
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Androck-Worcester Trips, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Ansul Chemical Company (Box 5)
  - Armed Forces Equipment, 1942-1946 (Box 5)
  - ARO Corporation, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Art Gallery Bulletin, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Art Metal Construction Company, 1958-1960; correspondence (Box 5)
  - Art Work (Box 5)
    See also Art Work and Charts below, at end of Business files series.
  - Arvin, 1967 (Box 5)
  - AS-1, 1961 (Box 5)
  - AS-2, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - ASID
    - Annual Meetings, 1962; 1964; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Committees, 1963 (Box 5)
    - Contact List, 1964-1970 (Box 5)
    - Convention Slides, 1960 (Box 5)
    - Educational Bulletins #5, 1962 (Box 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1964 (Box 5)
    - Inter Society Color Council, 1963 (Box 5)
    - Meeting, 1964 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 5)
    - Professional Evaluation Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 5)
    - Redefinition of ASID Position and Objectives, 1962-1963 (Box 5)
    - Talks, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - ASME Design Engineering Conference, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Association for the Advancement of Medical Instrumentation (AAMI), 1966 (Box 5)
  - Astatic Corporation
    - AS-2, Color, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Detail Sketches, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Headphones (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1968 (Box 5)
    - Typesetting, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Atlanta Sales Club Chart Slides (Box 5)
  - Baby Crib Market Research Report, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Background Data for Future RS Talks, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Baird Machine Co., 1961-1963 (Box 6)
  - Harold Barnett, 1962-1965 (Box 6)
  - Barrington and Company, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Allison Bayles, 1959-1961 (Box 6)
  - Beauti-Glide Company, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Beiges (Box 6)
  - Bennett Pump
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - 1965-1966, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Benrus
    - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Waterbury Manufacturing Division, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Better Built Machinery Corporation
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Reports and Proposals, 1971 (Box 6)
  - BIC Exhibits, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Bird and Son, Inc., 1962-1963; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Bostitch, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Boston Talk-IEEE Conference, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Bozak
    - Billing, 1961 (Box 6)
    - Bo-1 and -2, 1958-1968 (Box 6)
    - Bo-3, 1960-1961 (Box 6)
    - Bo-4, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Braun Engineering, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Brochure Covers, 1957-1959 (Box 6)
  - Brooks Stevens Associates (Box 6)
  - Brown and Sharpe, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - Buddy-L, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Buddy L. Corporation, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Budget and Schedule, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Business Cards (Box 6)
  - Canadian Johns-Manville Company, Limited
    - Billing, 1961 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 6)
  - Capewell (Box 6)
  - Cassette Tapes, 1969; 1972; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Cassette Tapes (Box 42)
  - Castle-Sybron, 1969 (Box 7)
  - CDA (Comprehensive Designers Association), 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Dave Chapman, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Charts, See Art Work and Charts below, at end of Business files series.
  - Chronolox, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Chronicle Occupational Briefs (Box 7)
  - Civil Defense (Box 7)
  - Civil Defense Program Conference (Box 7)
  - Clinton Engines, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Clippings and Reprints, 1950-1970 (Box 7)
  - CO-5, 1965 (Box 7)
  - CO-6, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Cober Electronics, Inc., 1970-1975 (Box 7)
  - Color Samples, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Columbia Manufacturing Company, Inc., 1961-1964 (Box 7)
  - Columbus Iron Works
    - CO-3 A and B, 1963 (Box 7)
    - CO-4, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Char-Broil Division
      - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
      - Sketches (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1969; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Gas Fired Cooker, 1965 (Box 7)
    - General Correspondence, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1969; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Planning Suggestions, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Recommendation for Industrial Design, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Colvin, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Company Contact Index Cards
    - Abb-Ame (Box 7)
    - Ame-Bal (Box 7)
    - Bal-Boo (Box 7)
    - Bor-Cas (Box 8)
    - Cas-Col (Box 8)
    - Com-Del (Box 8)
    - Dem-Elw (Box 8)
    - Emh-Gen (Box 8)
    - Gen-Gro (Box 8)
    - Gro-Hig (Box 8)
    - Hig-Jam (Box 8)
    - Jam-Lew (Box 8)
    - Lib-Max (Box 8)
    - May-Nat (Box 8)
    - Nat-Orb (Box 8)
    - Ort-Pra (Box 8)
    - Pre-Ric (Box 8)
    - Rid-Sco (Box 8)
    - Sco-Sou (Box 8)
    - Sou-Str (Box 9)
    - Stt-Toy (Box 9)
    - Tra-Var (Box 9)
    - Vee-Whe (Box 9)
    - Whi-Zep (Box 9)
  - Company Contact Records (Box 9)
  - Conditions (Box 9)
  - Copies of Atlanta Sales Executive Talk, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Cordley and Hayes, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Corporate Image Slide Material, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Corporate Image Slide Talk, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence with Colleges, 1966-1971 (Box 42)
  - Hamilton Cosco, Inc.
    - Annual Reports, 1963-1968 (Box 9)
    - Catalog, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Clippings About New Ideas, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Color Program Proposal, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Complete Catalogue (Box 9)
    - Competitive Ads, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Consultation Meeting Reports, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1970; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Cribs (Box 9)
    - Fabric/Color/Patterns (Box 9)
    - Folding Chair, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Folding Wire Chair, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Forms (Box 9)
    - Furniture, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
    - General Correspondence, 1963; 1966-1969; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - High Chair, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Industrial Drawings, 1963-1967; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Legal, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - Management Letters, 1967-1968 (Box 10)
    - Marketing Plans Meeting, 1966; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Meeting Reports, 1964-1966; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963-1974; undated; 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1965 (Box 10)
    - Office and Upholstered Furniture Division, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
    - Office Furniture, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Office Furniture Rough Notes and Sketches (Box 10)
    - Outside Supplier Catalogs, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Outside Supplier Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
    - Policy-Philosophy, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Preliminary Recommendation for Industrial Design Configuration, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Presentation Material, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Quote for Ordering Wholesale, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - Roughs, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
    - Space-Saver, 1965-1967 (Box 10)
    - Specification Drawings, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Study Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
    - Submission to IDI Award, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Trademark, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Course of Study in Industrial Design (Box 10)
  - Crib, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
  - CR-1, 1962-1963 (Box 11)
  - CR-2, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - CR-3
    - Detail Drawings, 1962-1963; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Hassock Vacuum Cleaner, 1962-1963 (Box 11)
    - Hasovac, 1964 (Box 11)
  - B.T. Crump Company
    - Brochures (Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1963 (Box 11)
    - Consultation Reports, 1961 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 11)
    - General Correspondence, 1960-1964; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964-1966; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - DCB General File, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Department of Commerce Commercial Fairs, 1965-1966 (Box 11)
  - Design Conference (Box 11)
  - The Designer-Management Relationship in the Corporate Structure, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Design Hope Enterprise, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Design Manual, 1960-1962 (Box 11)
  - Design Speech Transcript, 1953 (Box 11)
  - Desk Calendars
    - 1964 (Box 90)
    - 1964-1967, 7 folders (Box 11)
    - 1967-1969, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Dictation Disks, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Dow, 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Dow Chemical, 1966-1969 (Box 12)
  - Dow Corning Corporation, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Dow-Spilman Report, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Drafting Room Drawing Record Form, 1958; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Allen B. DuMont Laboratories, Inc., 1961 (Box 12)
  - Eagle Pencil Company, 1965-1967; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Thomas A. Edison, 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - Education, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Electrolux, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Electro-Mechanical Research, Inc., 1960-1964; general correspondence; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Emerson Electric Manufacturing Company, 1960-1962 (Box 12)
  - EMR
    - Billing Folder, 1960-1961 (Box 12)
    - Dynasoar (Box 12)
  - EMR-1, Dynasoar Proposal Consultation, 1960-1961 (Box 12)
  - Engineering Studies Frame, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Entry Form, "Design in America", 1962-1972 (Box 12)
  - Exercycle Corporation
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 12)
    - Structural Analysis (Box 12)
  - Exhibits, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - Exhibits Omitted, 1962-1963; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Farrington Manufacturing Company, 1959-1962 (Box 12)
  - Federal Safety Standards, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Finnell System, 1964 (Box 12)
  - Follow Up File, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Fordham Motor Sales (Box 12)
  - Foster-Grant, 1963-1967 (Box 12)
  - Furniture Methods and Materials, 1974 (Box 12)
  - General Electric Company, 1961-1963 (Box 13)
  - General Foods
    - Maxwell House, 1964-1965 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-1966; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - General Information Surveys, 1945 (Box 13)
  - General Motors Ashtray, Tape and Sample, 1935-1937 (Box 13)
  - General Thrift Corporation
    - Christmas Coupon Club, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 13)
    - [Miscellaneous], 1967 (Box 42)
  - Georgia Tech, 1956-1960; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Geoscience Nuclear, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Glacierware, 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - Glaser-Steers Corporation
    - Billing, 1961 (Box 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 13)
    - Proposals and Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 13)
  - B.F. Goodrich Catalogue (Box 13)
  - G.P.L. Camera, 1966 (Box 13)
  - W.R. Grace, 1972 (Box 13)
  - W.T. Grant Company, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Graphics, 1963 (Box 13)
  - Graphic Sciences, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - Grays, 1959 (Box 13)
  - L. Greene, 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - Gruen, 1972-1973 (Box 42)
  - GS-2C, Record Changer, 1962 (Box 13)
  - Halliwell, Inc.
    - Billing Folder, 1960-1961 (Box 13)
    - Catalogues (Box 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 13)
    - HAL-1, 1968-1969 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1957-1959 (Box 13)
  - Hard Manufacturing Company, 1968-1969 (Box 13)
  - Harvard Business Review, 1948 (Box 13)
  - HC Malone, 1966 (Box 13)
  - HC 1 Color Program, 1964 (Box 13)
  - HC 1, 2, 3 Portable Cribs, 1964 (Box 13)
  - HC-3-051, Preliminary Costing, 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - HC-3-052, Preliminary Costing, 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - HC-3-100, Cost Reduction, 1964-1966 (Box 13)
  - HC-4, 1965 (Box 13)
  - HC-6.1, -6.1A, 1966 (Box 13)
  - HC-6.2, 1966 (Box 13)
  - HC-6.4, 1966 (Box 13)
  - HC-8, Bar Stool, 1967; 1 volume, 1 folder (Box 13)
  - HC-9, Juvenile Dressing Table, 1968 (Box 13)
  - HC-BO, Booster Seat, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - HC-C, Design Program, 1964 (Box 13)
  - HCD, Sketches, 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - HCD-3
    - Crib Program, 1964 (Box 14)
    - Survey Notes (Box 14)
    - 3.1, 3.2, etc., 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - HCD-3.1, Cosco Car Crib, 1964 (Box 14)
  - HCD-4, 1964; 1965; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - HCD-4 and -5, 1965 (Box 14)
  - HCD-5, 1965 (Box 14)
  - HCG-1, 1966 (Box 14)
  - HCG-2, 1966-1967 (Box 14)
  - HCSS-1, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Heli-Coil Corporation
    - Miscellaneous, 1960-1967; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Slide Show and Proposal, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Prof. John F. Helm, Jr., 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - C.V. Hill and Company, Inc., 1950-1961 (Box 14)
  - Howe Catalogue (Box 14)
  - The Howell Company, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Howmet, 1969 (Box 14)
  - HR-1, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Harvey Hubbell, Inc., 1966-1970; miscellaneous; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - ICI
    - America Contract, 1971 (Box 14)
    - Parweb, 1971 (Box 14)
  - ICSID, 1967 (Box 14)
  - IDEA
    - Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 14)
    - Talk, 1961 (Box 14)
  - IDEAL Toy Corporation
    - Billing, 1964 (Box 14)
    - Fantasy Castle and Fantasy Palace, 1964 (Box 14)
    - ID-2, 1964 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964-1973; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "Petite Princess" Doll House, 1964 (Box 14)
  - IDI, 1961-1964 (Box 14)
  - IDL, 1966-1968 (Box 14)
  - ID Magazine, 1967 (Box 14)
  - IDSA
    - American Designer magazine, 1968 (Box 14)
    - Annual Committee Reports to the President, 1969 (Box 14)
    - Annual Reports, 1966-1968; 1970; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Awards and Scholarship, 1963-1965 (Box 14)
    - Board Meetings, 1960-1967 (Box 14)
    - Constitution and By-laws, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
    - Education, 1962-1969; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - General, 1964-1970; 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Meetings, 1965-1971; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Merger with IDEA, 1964-1966 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1973 (Box 15)
  - IMC Magnetics Corporation
    - Billing, 1962-1963 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 15)
    - Trademark (Box 15)
  - India, 1954-1957; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Industrial Designers Not Sent to Washburn, 1951-1967 (Box 15)
  - Industrial Design magazine, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Industrialization in Thailand, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Information About Booking Travel, 1963 (Box 15)
  - Information From "A Report to the President" (Box 15)
  - Ingraham Company, 1967-1968 (Box 15)
  - Inland Steel
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1970; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Roughs (Box 15)
  - Instrument Development Labs., Inc., 1964-1966 (Box 15)
  - International Council of Societies of Industrial Design, 1961-1965 (Box 15)
  - Inter-Society Color Council, 1966-1969; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Interstate, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - ISCC